Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association papers, 1922-1976
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association papers, 1922-1976
MS 426
Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association
Papers, 1922-1976 (bulk 1950-1957). This collection is comprised of the papers of the Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association. Items include organization files; publications; and reports. The bulk of the collection includes newsletters published by the Association and research materials. The research materials most likely come from a Mexican cattle survey conducted by the Agricultural Experiment Station at the University of Arizona, headed by Raymond E. Seltzer; included in the data sets are statistics, tallies and graphs.
1.75 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Historical Note
The Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association was founded in 1934 in Phoenix, Arizona by a group of Salt River Valley feeders. It is the oldest cattle feeders' organization in the United States. The main purpose of the organization is to assist cattlemen with marketing. Today, the Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association is managed by the Arizona Cattlemen's Association which is responsible for administering the policies and programs of both the Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association and the Arizona Cattle Growers' Association.
The collection also includes research materials from Dr. Raymond Seltzer. Dr. Seltzer was a professor at the University of Arizona in agricultural economics. He worked with the cattle industry and conducted the Mexican cattle survey. Raymond Eugene Seltzer was born in 1918 in Illinois. He received his Bachelor of Science from the University of Illinois. He received his Master of Science from Kansas State University and his Ph.D. from the University of California, Berkeley in Agricultural Economics in 1957. In 1947 was became a professor at the University of Arizona in agricultural economics. He served as chair of the department from 1957 to 1961. In 1961 Dr. Seltzer started Agri Research Inc (later renamed Development Planning and Research Associates) which was an international consulting firm in agricultural, environmental and engineering research. Dr. Seltzer retired in 1983 and after moving back to Tucson, Arizona, taught at the American Graduate School of International Management.
Organization
This collection is organized into 3 series:
Series 1: Organization Files, 1959-1962
Series 2: Reports, 1945-1976
Series 3: Publications, 1922-1963
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1922-1976 (bulk 1950-1957). This collection contains papers from the Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association. The bulk of the collection consists of newsletters published by the Association concerning market analysis of the cattle market and Association news as well as data sets including statistics and graphs related to the Mexican cattle trade with the United States. The data sets most likely come from Dr. Seltzer's research on a Mexican cattle survey from 1955-1957.
Access Terms
Arizona Cattle Feeders Association.
Cattle trade--Arizona.
Cattle--Arizona.
Container List
- Series 1: Organization Files, 1959-1962
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains material related to the Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association including a membership roster and annual meeting programs.
  - Annual meeting programs. 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership roster. 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Publications, 1945-1976
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains material published by the Arizona Cattle Feeders' Association including a magazine and monthly newsletters.
  - Magazine- Arizona, the Feeders' Choice. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters. 1945-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters. 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters. 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters. 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series 3: Reports, 1922-1963
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains reports from the Agricultural Experiment Station at the University of Arizona and data sets from a Mexican cattle survey. The data sets include statistics, tallies and graphs.
  - Arizona Livestock Slaughter. 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Consumer Preference for Beef. 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Costs and Returns Data for Representative General Crop Farms in Arizona. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Data Sets- Arizona cattle slaughter. 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Data Sets- Arizona cattle slaughter. 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Data Sets- Breed, class and purpose. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Data Sets- Calexico. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Data Sets- Cattle shipments. 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Data Sets- Cattle shipments. 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Data Sets- Cattle shipments. 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Data Sets- Cattle weights. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Data Sets- Concentration by owner. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Data Sets- Destination in U.S. 1922-1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Data Sets- Importation trends. 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Data Sets- Imports of Mexican cattle. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Data Sets- Imports of Mexican cattle through Arizona ports. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Data Sets- Imports of Mexican cattle through New Mexico ports. 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Data Sets- Imports of Mexican cattle through Texas ports. 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Data Sets- Locality of origin of Mexican cattle imported into the U.S. 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Data Sets- Mexican owners. 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Data Sets- Origin in Mexico. 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Data Sets- Rejects (cattle). 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Data Sets- Seasonal variation in imports. 1930-1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Data Sets- U.S. importers. 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Performance in U.S. 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)